A Guide to the Richmond Friends Meeting Records, 1849-2004
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Richmond Friends Meeting Records, 1849-2004 (bulk 1914-2004)
Library of Virginia
40877
33 microfilm reels (ca. 11 cubic feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Use microfilm (Misc. reels 4659-4691)
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Richmond Friends Meeting, 29 September 2003 and 28 May 2004.
Historical Information
In 1795, a Richmond Indulged Meeting was organized under the care of the White Oak Swamp Monthly Meeting. When the Weyanoke Monthly Meeting (formerly known as the White Oak Swamp Monthly Meeting) was disbanded in 1841, its members joined the Richmond Particular or Preparative Meeting, which then became part of the Cedar Creek Monthly Meeting. In 1844, the Richmond Meeting was suspended under an agreement that the Cedar Creek Monthly Meeting would meet occasionally in Richmond. By 1854, the Monthly Meeting was only meeting in Richmond. In 1875, the Cedar Creek Monthly Meeting officially changed its name to the Richmond Monthly Meeting.
The Richmond Monthly Meeting is part of the Baltimore Yearly Meeting.
Scope and Content
Records, 1849-2004 (bulk 1914-2004), of the Richmond Friends Meeting, including committee files, correspondence, financial records, historical materials, membership records, minutes, newsletters, publications, and reports that document Quaker history and tradition in Richmond and Virginia. These records also detail the meeting's involvement in the war tax resistance movement, helping war refugees since World War I with the American Friends Service Committee, and social issues, such as same-sex marriage and terminal illness.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series and subseries:
I. Monthly Meeting Minutes, 1963-1999 (Misc. reels 4659-4663)
II. Clerk (Misc. reel 4664)
III. Recorder (Misc. reel 4664)
IV. Treasurer, 1914-1985 (Misc. reel 4664)
V. Meeting Historian (Misc. reels 4665-4667)
VI. Committee Files (Misc. reels 4668-4681)
Subseries A. Ad Hoc Committee on the Clearing (Misc. reel 4668)
Subseries B. Ad Hoc Committee on Growth (Misc. reel 4668)
Subseries C. Advancement and Outreach Study (Misc. reel 4668)
Subseries D. Bicentennial (Misc. reel 4668)
Subseries E. Buildings and Grounds (Misc. reels 4669-4670)
Subseries F. Care and Counsel (Misc. reels 4671-4672)
Subseries G. Clearing (Misc. reel 4673)
Subseries H. Financial Stewardship (Misc. reel 4673)
Subseries I. Ministry and Counsel (Misc. reel 4673)
Subseries J. Ministry and Worship (Misc. reel 4673)
Subseries K. Peace (Misc. reel 4673)
Subseries L. Peace Education (Misc. reels 4674-4675)
Subseries M. Religious Education (Misc. reels 4676-4680)
Subseries N. Spring Retreat (Misc. reel 4681)
Subseries O. Trustees (Misc. reel 4681)
VII. Membership Records, 1849-1998 (Misc. reels 4682-4684)
VIII. Newsletters, 1956-2001 (Misc. reels 4685-4688)
IX. American Friends Service Committee (Misc. reel 4688)
X. War Tax Resistance (Misc. reel 4689)
XI. Virginia Quarterly Meeting, 1961-1975 (Misc. reel 4690)
XII. Representative Meeting, 25 October 1997 (Misc. reel 4690)
XIII. Ashland Friends Meeting, 1991-1999 (Misc. reel 4690)
XIV. Midlothian Friends Meeting, 1988-1995 (Misc. reel 4691)
XV. Publications (NOT MICROFILMED)
Arrangement of Microfilm:
Misc. reel 4659 contains: Series I: Monthly Meeting Minutes, 1963-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1-12)
Misc. reel 4660 contains: Series I: Monthly Meeting Minutes, 1963-1999 (Box 1, Folder 13-20)
Misc. reel 4661 contains: Series I: Monthly Meeting Minutes, 1963-1999 (Box 1, Folder 21-27)
Misc. reel 4662 contains: Series I: Monthly Meeting Minutes, 1963-1999 (Box 1, Folder 28 - Box 2, Folder 3)
Misc. reel 4663 contains: Series I: Monthly Meeting Minutes, 1963-1999 (Box 2, Folder 4-11)
Misc. reel 4664 contains: Series II: Clerk; Series III: Recorder; Series IV: Treasurer, 1914-1985 (Box 2, Folders 12-29)
Misc. reel 4665 contains: Series V: Meeting Historian (Box 2, Folder 30-48)
Misc. reel 4666 contains: Series V: Meeting Historian (Box 2, Folder 49 - Box 3, Folder 4)
Misc. reel 4667 contains: Series V: Meeting Historian (Box 3, Folder 5-18)
Misc. reel 4668 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries A-D (Box 3, Folder 19-38)
Misc. reel 4669 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries E (Box 3, Folder 39-47)
Misc. reel 4670 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries E (Box 3, Folder 48 - Box 4, Folder 6)
Misc. reel 4671 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries F (Box 4, Folder 7-21)
Misc. reel 4672 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries F (Box 4, Folder 22-31)
Misc. reel 4673 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries G-K (Box 4, Folder 32-57)
Misc. reel 4674 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries L (Box 5, Folder 1-17)
Misc. reel 4675 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries L (Box 5, Folder 18-29)
Misc. reel 4676 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries M (Box 5, Folder 30-53)
Misc. reel 4677 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries M (Box 5, Folder 54 - Box 6, Folder 9)
Misc. reel 4678 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries M (Box 6, Folder 10-23)
Misc. reel 4679 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries M (Box 6, Folder 24-29)
Misc. reel 4680 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries M (Box 6, Folder 30-40)
Misc. reel 4681 contains: Series VI: Committee Files, Subseries N-O (Box 6, Folder 41-51)
Misc. reel 4682 contains: Series VII: Membership Records, 1849-1998 (Box 6, Folder 52 - Box 7, Folder 8)
Misc. reel 4683 contains: Series VII: Membership Records, 1849-1998 (Box 7, Folder 9-17)
Misc. reel 4684 contains: Series VII: Membership Records, 1849-1998 (Box 7, Folder 18-35)
Misc. reel 4685 contains: Series VIII: Newsletters, 1956-2001 (Box 7, Folder 36-43)
Misc. reel 4686 contains: Series VIII: Newsletters, 1956-2001 (Box 7, Folder 44 - Box 8, Folder 6)
Misc. reel 4687 contains: Series VIII: Newsletters, 1956-2001 (Box 8, Folder 7-11)
Misc. reel 4688 contains: Series VIII: Newsletters, 1956-2001; Series IX: American Friends Service Committee (Box 8, Folder 12-22)
Misc. reel 4689 contains: Series X: War Tax Resistance (Box 8, Folder 23-33)
Misc. reel 4690 contains: Series XI: Virginia Quarterly Meeting, 1961-1975; Series XII: Representative Meeting, 25 Oct. 1997; Series XIII. Ashland Friends Meeting, 1991-1999 (Box 8, Folder 34-41)
Misc. reel 4691 contains: Series XIV. Midlothian Friends Meeting, 1988-1995 (Box 9, Folder 1-13)
Contents List
- Monthly Meeting Minutes, 1963-1996 (Box 1-2, Reel 4659-4663)
  Includes meeting minutes, committee reports, treasurer's reports, budget and financial records, attendance lists, and membership records that document the activities of the Richmond Friends Meeting, including the meeting's various committees.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1982 (Jan. - June) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1982 (July - Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1983 (Jan. - Apr.) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1983 (May - Aug.) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1983 (Sept. - Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1984 (Jan. - June) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1984 (July - Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1985 (Jan. - June) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1985 (July - Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1986 (Jan. - June) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1986 (July - Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1987 (Jan. - June) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1987 (July - Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1988 (Jan. - June) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1988 (July - Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1989 (Jan. - June) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1989 (July - Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1993 (Jan. - June) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1993 (July - Dec.) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1994 (Jan. - June) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1994 (July - Dec.) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1995 (Jan. - June) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1995 (July - Dec.) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1996 (Jan. - June) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1996 (July - Dec.) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Clerk (Box 2, Reel 4664)
  Consists of records of the clerk of the Richmond Friends Meeting, including correspondence, memos, reports, newsletters, and brochures. These records concern meeting business, communications between the Monthly meeting and the Yearly meeting, contributions, committee clerking, and the realignment of the Quarterly meeting.
  - Clerking (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence 1960-1995 (bulk 1989-1991) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Quarterly Meetings Realignment (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Recorder (Box 2, Reel 4664)
  This series includes a handbook on the creation, maintenance, and preservation of Meeting records, and reports and memos concerning the role of the Meeting Recorder.
  - Handbook on Records (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Reports and Memos, 1994, 1996, n.d (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Treasurer, 1914-1985 (Box 2, Reel 4664)
  Contains a bank deposit book recording deposits in the Savings Bank of Richmond for the years 1915-1917, bills, 1917-1921, budgets, 1974-1985, cancelled checks, 1916-1921, incoming and outgoing correspondence, 1916-1992, expenditures, 1914-1918, flip charts highlighting operating expenses and the proposed budget for 1959, receipts, 1916-1922, and a treasurer's account book, 1917-1935. These records document the financial history of the Richmond Friends Meeting. Of note is the correspondence and cancelled checks concerning the fundraising activities of the Richmond Friends Meeting for various charities.
  - Bank Deposit Book, 1915-1917 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bills, 1917-1921 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Budgets, 1974-1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1916-1919 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Incoming, 1915-1922 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, Outgoing, 1916-1918 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Expenditures, 1914-1918 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Flip Charts Outlining Operating Expenses and Proposed Budget, 1959
  - Receipts, 1916-1922 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Receipts, YMCA, 1916-1922 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Treasurer's Book of the Richmond Monthly Meeting of the Society of Friends, 1917-1935
- Meeting Historian (Box 2-3, Reel 4665-4667)
  Includes materials relating to Quaker history and tradition, the history of Quakers in Richmond and Virginia, and the history of the Richmond Friends Meeting. Of note are the materials documenting Richmond Quakers during the Civil War, and efforts to save the Jacob House from being destroyed in the expansion of Virginia Commonwealth University. Also includes an article on the John Miller House, photocopies of the journals of Elias Hicks and John Woolman, agendas and minutes of the History Committee from August 1992 to September 1993, research notes and rough drafts of the history of Richmond Friends Meeting written by Mary Fran Hughes, correspondence containing information on Quaker history and requests for information, and records of the Friends Christian Endeavor Society.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Basic Quaker Philosophies and Folk Music (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Caroline County Quakers (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Cedar Creek Monthly Meeting (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1996 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Friends Buried in Hollywood Cemetery (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Friends Christian Endeavor Society (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "A Genealogical History of the Chappell, Dickie, and Other Kindred Families of Virginia" (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Historical Homecoming Committee (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - History Committee Agenda and Minutes, Aug. 1992 - Sept. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "The History of Richmond Friends Meeting, 1795-1962" by Mary Fran Hughes (1979) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "The History of Richmond Friends Meeting, 1795-1962" - Research Materials (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "The History of Richmond Friends Meeting, 1795-1962" - Research Notes (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "The History of Richmond Friends Meeting, 1795-1962" - Rough Drafts (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Jacob House - Complete Documentation (I-V) (Box 2, Folder 44-48)
  - Jacob House - Correspondence, Oct. 1994 - May 1995 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Jacob House - Correspondence, June - July 1995, June - July 1996 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Jacob House - Newsclippings (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Jacob House - Press Releases and Publicity (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "The John Miller House - 617 S. Cherry Street Built, Owned, and Occupied by Free African-Americans in Antebellum Richmond" (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Journal of Elias Hicks (p. 7-25, 122-123, 132-183) (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Journal of John Woolman (p. 1-223) (Box 2, Folder 55-56)
  - Loudoun County Quakers (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Magazine Articles re. Quaker History and Tradition (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Places (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Photograph of the Fourth World Conference of Friends, 1967
  - Princess Anne County Quakers (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Reynolds Fund Grants (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Area Association for Retarded Citizens - 50th Anniversary (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Richmond Friends' Meeting, 1795-1983" (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Richmond Friends Meeting Pamphlet (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Richmond Quakers During the Civil War (copies of records in the National Archives) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Ricks Memorial Lecture (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook Shelf (newsclippings and photographs reserved for scrapbook) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Some Information About the Two Baltimore Yearly Meetings (1964) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Quaker Records (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Women's Meeting (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous (I-II) (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
- Committee Files (Box 3-6, Reel 4668-4681)
  Includes files of the following committees: Ad Hoc Committee on the Clearing, Ad Hoc Committee on Growth, Advancement and Outreach Study, Bicentennial, Buildings and Grounds, Care and Counsel, Clearing, Financial Stewardship, Ministry and Counsel, Ministry and Worship, Peace, Peace Education, Religious Education, Spring Retreat, and Trustees.
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Clearing (Box 3, Reel 4668)
    Includes reports, minutes, and background information of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Clearing, created to study the ongoing management of the Clearing, property the Richmond Friends Meeting owns in Amelia County, Virginia for the purpose of religious retreats and gatherings. The background information includes reports and minutes of the Clearing Committee and Business Meeting regarding the history and maintenance of the Clearing since its donation in the early 1980's.
    - Clearing Committee and Business Meeting Records, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Minutes, Feb. - Oct. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Proposal for the Ad Hoc Committee to Review Management of the Clearing (draft), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous (receipts and notes) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Growth (Box 3, Reel 4668)
    This ad hoc committee was organized to explore the issues surrounding the continued growth of the Richmond Friends Meeting. Includes minutes, reports, and notes.
    - Minutes, Mar. - Oct. 1995, Jan. 1996, Oct. 1997 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Reports and Notes (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Advancement and Outreach Study (Box 3, Reel 4668)
    Includes minutes, correspondence, and reports, 1985, of the Advancement and Outreach Study Committee, organized to determine whether the Richmond Friends Meeting needed an outreach committee.
    - Minutes, Correspondence, and Reports, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Bicentennial (Box 3, Reel 4668)
    This series includes correspondence, financial records, invitations, log books, minutes, newsletter articles, press releases, programs, and reports, concerning the organizing, publicizing, and celebrating of the 200th anniversary of the Richmond Friends Meeting in 1995. The log books contain a monthly account of the planning of the bicentennial celebration.
    - Bicentennial Celebration Program (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Budget Files and Receipts (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, Dec. 1994 - Nov. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence re. Exhibits, May - Aug. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Exhibit Materials (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Invitations, Accepted (A-K) (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Invitations, Accepted (L-Z) (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Invitations, Declined (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Invitation Drafts (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Log for Bicentennial Planning, 29 Oct. 199 4- 26 Sept. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Mailing and Guest Lists (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Minutes and Reports to Business Meeting, Mar. 1994, Nov. 1994 - Aug. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Press Releases and Newsletter Articles (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Buildings and Grounds (Box 3-4, Reel 4669-4670)
    This series includes calendars, correspondence, financial records, memos, minutes and agendas, receipts, reports, concerning the care and upkeep of the building and grounds from 1977 to 1995. Also includes architectural drawings for the handicapped access ramps and other materials for making the Meeting House ADA compliant.
    - 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - 1986 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - 1987 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - 1988 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - 1990 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - 1991 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - 1992 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - 1993 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Architectural Drawings for Handicapped Access Ramp
    - Committee Clerk (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Information and Procedures (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Meeting House - ADA Compliance (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Care and Counsel (Box 4, Reel 4671-4672)
    This committee is responsible for overseeing marriages, and helping members cope with illness, personal problems, material needs, and death. This series contains material relating to a variety of topics germane to the activities of the committee, including burial, cremation, and organ donation, death and dying, hospice care, terminal illness, living wills, memorial societies, marriage, same-sex marriage, sex education. Also includes committee minutes for March-November 1981 and April 1982.
    - Burial, Cremation, and Organ and Body Donation (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Death and Dying - General (I-III) (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
    - Hospice - Terminal Illness (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Living Will (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Marriage (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Memorial Societies (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Minutes, Mar. - Nov. 1981, Apr. 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Planning Ahead (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Requests for Marriage Under the Care of the Meeting (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Richmond Memorial Society (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Quaker Marriage Information (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Same-Sex Marriage (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Sample Certificate for Friends Marriage Ceremony
    - Sex Education (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Wendell Williams' Files on Death and Dying - Concern for Dying/Choice in Dying Newsletter (I-II) (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
    - Wendell Williams' Files on Death and Dying - Funerals, Cremation, Memorial Services, Costs, Arrangements (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Wendell Williams' Files on Death and Dying - General (I-II) (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
    - Wendell Williams' Files on Death and Dying - Hospice, Death, and Dignity Cases (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Wendell Williams' Files on Death and Dying - Living Will and Medical Power of Attorney (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Wendell Williams' Files on Death and Dying - Memorial Society of Greater Richmond Area (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Wendell Williams' Files on Death and Dying - Memorial Societies (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Clearing (Box 4, Reel 4673)
    This committee is responsible for the maintenance of the Clearing, property the Richmond Friends Meeting owns in Amelia County, Virginia for the purpose of religious retreats and gatherings. This series consists of a report to the business meeting, dated 21 May 2000.
    - Report to Business Meeting, 21 May 2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Financial Stewardship (Box 4, Reel 4673)
    This committee is responsible for handling the financial matters of the Richmond Friends Meeting. Includes budget request guidelines for 1998, and minutes for 7 February 1993.
    - Budget Request Guidelines, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Minutes, 7 Feb. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Ministry and Counsel (Box 4, Reel 4673)
    Includes correspondence, 4 June 1963 and 28 January 1966, and minutes, December 1974, April-May, 1976, October 1976, February-March 1980, and September-October 1980. The correspondence concerns meetings and the minutes document the activities of the Ministry and Counsel committee. In 1981, this committee became the Ministry and Worship Committee.
    - Correspondence, 4 June 1963, 28 Jan. 1966 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Minutes, Dec. 1974, Apr. - May 1976, Oct. 1976, Feb. - Mar. 1980, Sept. - Oct. 1980 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Ministry and Worship (Box 4, Reel 4673)
    This committee is responsible for holding meetings for worship, marriages, and memorials, and nurturing the spiritual state of the meeting. This series consists of correspondence, memos, minutes, and reports concerning the activities of the committee. Includes files relating to death, eldering, and same-sex unions, as well as minutes, 1987-1992 and Spiritual state of the meeting reports from 1956, 1975-1990, of which the earlier ones were generated by the Ministry and Counsel Committee. Also includes information relating to the Ashland Indulged Meeting, Farmville Indulged Meeting, and Midlothian Preparative Meeting. The Ministry and Worship Committee is responsible for assisting in the organization of worship meetings outside of the Richmond Monthly Meeting.
    - Activities, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Ashland Indulged Meeting (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Death (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Education of Ministry and Worship Committee (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Eldering (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Farmville Indulged Meeting (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Meeting-for-Worship Room (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Membership Lists (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Midlothian Preparative Meeting (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Minutes, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Minutes, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Same-Sex Unions (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Spiritual State of Meeting, 1956, 1975-1990 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Peace (Box 4, Reel 4673)
    Includes newspaper advertisements, correspondence, publications, and reports concerning the efforts of Quakers to keep the United States out of World War I and help the ease the suffering of war refugees. Of note is a copy of an interview with Count Tolstoi discussing Russian Relief.
    - Advertisements against War, [1916] (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Annual Report, [1916] (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1916 - Apr. 1917, Apr. 1920 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence re. European Relief Funds, 1916-1921 (bulk 1920) (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Publications (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Russian Relief (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Peace Education (Box 5, Reel 4674-4675)